# Toan Mach

#### **Photo Editor**

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Toan-Mach/95621f509a5cd4e9

Pursuing a career opportunity in a company or a brand where my creativity, innovation and fashion expertise can enhance its business while maintaining its mission statements. I am highly artistic, adaptive to new challenges and willing to relocate.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Photo Editor**

Fashion - Philadelphia, PA - 2011 to 2011

2011

FunTimes Magazine, Philadelphia, PA

Primary photographer/photo editor on all monthly fashion spreads, involving communicating/booking/styling models for shoots. In addition to interviews, producing written stories and designing layouts such as personal profiles and reviews. Oversee the entire layout of the magazine as a whole.

#### **Chief Editor**

A Mach Moment - State College, PA - 2010 to 2011

Producer in pitching, writing, booking, styling, editing, photographing and designing of the book.

## **Receptionist/ Office Assistant**

Office for Disability Services - State College, PA - 2007 to 2011

PR position involving guiding visitors through the registration process, scheduling appointments/meetings for students and staff. Occasionally resolved issues from clients under pressure and lack of supervision/assistance.

AWARD/AFFILIATIONS: Congressional Awards: Bronze, Silver and Gold Medalist Fellowship Chair, Alpha Phi Omega, National Honor Service Fraternity Dean's List, College of Communications & College of Arts and Architecture

## Fashion Writer/Reporter

FunTimes Magazine - Philadelphia, PA - 2010 to 2010

Researched, wrote and designed articles and ads, attended and covered fashion shows, concerts and social events to promote the magazine. Those interviewed included fashion designers, artists and priority guests.

# Founder/Editor-in-chief

M]ASCULINE Magazine - State College, PA - 2009 to 2010

Wrote the proposal, advertised the brand and recruited members through informational meetings. Regulated the magazine as a whole: Editorial, Art, Public Relations. Led assemblies with staff to discuss the production.

#### **Assistant Creative Director**

Valley Magazine - State College, PA - 2008 to 2009

Incorporated themes for fashion spreads while directing/managing photo shoots to correspond.

# **EDUCATION**

Pennsylvania State University

# **B.A.** in Print Journalism

College of Communications

# **B.A.** in Integrative Arts

College of Arts and Architecture

# **SKILLS**

General: Reporting, styling, public relations, customer service, creative writing, audio editing

# LINKS

http://issuu.com/toan.mach/docs/1st\_volume \_\_print\_compressed

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# SKILLS:

General: Reporting, styling, public relations, customer service, creative writing, audio editing

Programs: Adobe Photoshop/InDesign/Flash/Dreamweaver, Microsoft Office Suite/Publisher, QuarkXPress

Languages: Fluent in Vietnamese, advanced Cantonese, basic conversational Mandarin